[
  {
    "question": "Which Norwegian polar explorer built the first base on the Antarctic continent?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      "Roald Amundsen",
      "Otto Sverdrup",
      "Carsten Borchgrevink",
      "Fridtjof Nansen"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Carsten Borchgrevink"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the elevation (in meters above sea level) at the South Pole?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      "820",
      "1525",
      "2390",
      "2835"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "2835"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the largest species of penguin?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      "King",
      "Emperor",
      "Gentoo",
      "Adelie"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Emperor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which country was not one of the original 12 signatories of the Antarctic Treaty?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      "Germany",
      "Chile",
      "Belgium",
      "Japan"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Germany"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the term for the early stage of sea ice, where solid pieces have formed but the surface is not yet solid?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      "Spot ice",
      "Pancake ice",
      "Growlers",
      "Bergy bits"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Pancake ice"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following gemstones is not a variety of quartz?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      "Tourmaline",
      "Amethyst",
      "Citrine",
      "Onyx"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Tourmaline"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following geologic periods is the oldest?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      "Permian",
      "Jurassic",
      "Cretacious",
      "Cambrian"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Cambrian"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which property of a mineral can be indicated using the Mohs scale?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      "Color",
      "Streak",
      "Hardness",
      "Transparency"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Hardness"
  },
  {
    "question": "What kind of lava is typically formed from the eruption of underwater volcanic vents?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      "Pillow lava",
      "Block lava",
      "A'a",
      "Pahoehoe"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Pillow lava"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which volcano contains the world's largest lava lake?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      "Mount Erebus",
      "Mount Etna",
      "Mount Nyiragongo",
      "Mount Merapi"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Mount Nyiragongo"
  },
  {
    "question": "What animal appears on the flag of the Turks and Caicos Islands?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      "turtle",
      "lion",
      "lobster",
      "albatross"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "lobster"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many states make up the United States of America?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      "45",
      "48",
      "50",
      "52"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "50"
  },
  {
    "question": "Nagasaki is located on which of the main Japanese islands?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      "Honshu",
      "Kyushu",
      "Shikoku",
      "Hokkaido"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Kyushu"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the official language of The Gambia?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      "French",
      "English",
      "Swahili",
      "Yoruba"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "English"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2018, the country of Swaziland changed its name to what?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      "Eswatini",
      "Lilangeni",
      "Siyinqaba",
      "Mbabane"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Eswatini"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Star Wars Episode IV, where is the location of the hidden rebel base?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      "Dantooine",
      "Tatooine",
      "Yavin 4",
      "Hoth"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Yavin 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which actor has played James Bond in the most films?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      "Sean Connery",
      "Roger Moore",
      "Pierce Brosnan",
      "Daniel Craig"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Roger Moore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the pirate in The Goonies?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      "Long John Silver",
      "Blackbeard",
      "Dread Pirate Roberts",
      "One-Eyed Willy"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "One-Eyed Willy"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of The Princess Bride?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      "Buttercup",
      "Elise",
      "Aura",
      "Mary"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Buttercup"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the call sign of Mike Metcalf, the lead instructor in Top Gun?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      "Jester",
      "Viper",
      "Wolfman",
      "Slider"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Viper"
  }
]